RESUME

Vivek Mengu

Senior Software Engineer II

I'm an Application Engineer with 7yrs work experience.

Experienced in developing ReactJs web applications with modern technologies like Typescript, Redux, Saga, Webpack. Hands-on experience in improving application performance and code optimization. Have built SAAS applications from scratch to production ready and also worked on major Headless CMS.

Address:

404 / 1, Shree Shiv Sai Society, Hasu Tandel Marg. Prabhadevi Mumbai - 400025.

+91 8169979459

vivek.mengu016@gmail.com

SKILLS

HTML, CSS / SCSS, JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, ReactJs, Redux, Saga, React Final Form, Gatsby, NextJs, NodeJS, Express, Jest, Cypress, Git, Jira, Wordpress, Ghost, Strapi and a strong understanding of Headless CMS & Frontend libraries.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Developed existing AngularJs application in ReactJs using
 Redux, Saga, Typescript, and Webpack 4 with reusable code.
- Developed isolated UI components using StorybookJs, Error handling and data validation.
- Implemented Webpack with env-based code optimization and proxy to different API servers, and aliases for common components.
- Added route-based chunks using Webpack magic comments.
- Improved application performance and code optimization.
- Have an understanding of how micro frontend works and implement the same.
- Helping other teammates solve bugs and guiding them to write better business logic and provide effective solutions.

- Good hold on Nginx, AWS lambda, Cloud functions, firestore.
- Have got exposure to an agile way of working.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Contentstack / Senior Software Engineer II

Feb 2019 - PRESENT, Mumbai (Virar)

OneDigiLTA / Frontend Engineer

June 2018 - Nov 2018, Bangalore (Electronic City)

GoPBN / Frontend Developer Lead

May 2016 - May 2018, Mumbai (Thane)

WisdmLabs / Frontend Developer

Mar 2015 - Apr 2016, Mumbai (Thane)

WisdmLabs / Frontend Developer - Intern

Mar 2014 - Apr 2015, Mumbai (Thane)

EDUCATION

Vidyalankar School of Information Technology / BSc.IT

2012 - 2015, Mumbai

Andhra Education Society Jr College / Computer Science (H.S.C)

2010 - 2012, Mumbai

Andhra Education Society High School / (S.S.C)

Till 2010. Mumbai

I hereby declare that the above-described information is accurate to the best of my knowledge and bear the responsibility for its accuracy.

Date: (Vivek Mengu)